A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Communications, SG 2, Series 5 FA481
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Communications, SG 2, Series 5
1920-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA481
25.25 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Biographical / Historical
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
Separated Materials
Special format items (audio, film, video, digital media, library material, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the body of the collection. Each item is assigned a unique seperation number, as noted. Request to access open speacial formats should reference the unique separation number.
Arrangement
1. Administration. 2. Clippings. 3. London Forum 4. Programs. 5. Publications. 6. Special Formats.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: correspondence, clippings, programs, and publications.
- Communications, 5
  - Administration, 1
    - Annual Report Publicity, 1953-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Communications Office - The Commonwealth Fund Report to the Board, 1988 July - 1995 April (Box 1, Folder 2, Folder 3)
    - Denis Lehane, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Division of Unemployment, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dowling Manuscript, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Executive Nurse Stationary and Brochure, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ginsberg Manuscript, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harkness Family, 1983, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Harkness House Brochure, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Contracts, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Correction, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Distribution, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Erin Gray, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Galleys, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Invoices, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Invoices, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Paul Goldberg, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Harkness House Brochure - Production and Printing, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Harkness House Evenings and Functions, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Harkness House History, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Harkness House History - Hamann, Gray, and Goldberger, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Harkness House Photo History, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Harkness House Stationary, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Health Affairs - John Iglehart, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Louis Harris Survey - Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Louis Harris Survey - Invoices, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Marcus Source Book and Invoices, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Margo Horn - Current, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Master - Harris Commission Survey, 1986 July (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Medicaid Home Care Capitation, Phase I Interim Project Report, 1995 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Photography - Invoices, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Problems Facing Elderly Americans Living Alone, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 2
    - Americans Over 55 At Work Program - Research Reports 1 and 2, 1990 Jan. 25 - March 8 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Commission on Women's Health - Domestic Violence - Media Coverage of Programs, 1996 April-Sept. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Commission on Women's Health - Women's Health - Related Behaviors and Use of Clinical Preventive Services - Media Coverage, also Fact Sheets and Pamphlet of Work in Progress., 1995 Nov. - 1996 Feb. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Harkness Fellowships - UK Preliminary Report on Outcomes Selected Press Clippings, 1990 Oct. - 1992 Oct. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Harkness House - Memorandum - Recent Media Coverage and Selected Press Clippings, 1994 Nov. - 1995 April (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Americans Over 55 At Work Programs, 1990 November-1991 June (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Americans Over 55 At Work Programs, 1992 April-October (Box 5, Folder 40, Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Americans Over 55 At Work Programs, 1992 November-1993 March (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Americans Over 55 At Work Programs, 1993 April-June (Box 6, Folder 44, Folder 43)
    - Americans Over 55 At Work Programs, 1993 November-1994 April (Box 6, Folder 46, Folder 45)
    - Corporate Case Studies, 1991 May-August (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Corporate Case Studies, 1991 July-Nov. (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Health Care Coverage and Access and Picker-Commonwealth Fund Program on Health Care Quality and Managed Care, 1996 April-Oct. 15 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1989 November-1990 March (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1990 April-June (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1990 June-October (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1990 November-1991 June (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1991 July-November (Box 8, Folder 55, Folder 54)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1991 November-1992 April (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1992 April-October (Box 8, Folder 58, Folder 57)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1992 November-1993 March (Box 9, Folder 60, Folder 59)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1993 April-June (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1993 July-October (Box 10, Folder 63, Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1993 November-1994 April (Box 10, Folder 64, Folder 65)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1994 April-June (Box 11, Folder 66, Folder 67)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1994 July-November (Box 11, Folder 68, Folder 69)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1994 November-1995 April (Box 12, Folder 70, Folder 71)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1995 April-July (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1995 July-November (Box 12, Folder 73, Box 13, Folder 74)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1995 November-1996 April (Box 13, Folder 75)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1996 April-June (Box 13, Folder 76)
    - Commonwealth Fund Programs, 1996 July-1997 May (Box 14, Folder 77)
    - Summary of Media Coverage - Advancing the Well-Being of Elderly People, 1996 Jan.-Nov. (Box 14, Folder 78)
    - Summary of the Media Coverage - Bettering the Health of Minority Americans, 1995 March - 1996 Oct. 15 (Box 14, Folder 79)
    - Summary of Media Coverage - Commonwealth Programs, 1996 July-October 15 (Box 14, Folder 80)
    - Survey of Women's Health, 1993 July-October (Box 14, Folder 81)
  - London Forum, 3
    - Annual Report Request, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 82)
    - Australia - Sisney Sax, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 83)
    - Australia - Bruce Ford, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 84)
    - Canada - Robert Evans, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 85)
    - Canada - J. Ronald D. Bayne, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 86)
    - Caring for Elderly People, 1983, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 87)
    - Caring for the Elderly in America - There is a Choice - Schroeder, S. A., 1988 (Box 15, Folder 88)
    - Chartbook - Correspondence, 1988 Sept. (Box 15, Folder 89)
    - Contract, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 90)
    - Elderly People, 1983 May (Box 15, Folder 91)
    - Elderly Papers and Travel Information, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 92)
    - Foreword - MEM, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 93)
    - General Folder, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 94)
    - Introduction - Schroeder, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 95)
    - New Zealand - John Campbell, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 96)
    - New Zealand - Brian Easton, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 97)
    - Original Manuscript - Care for the Geriatric Patients in the United States, 1982, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 98)
    - Good Health and the Elderly, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 99)
    - Originals - Good Health and the Elderly, 1980's (Box 17, Folder 100, Folder 101)
    - Overview - Steven A. Schroeder, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 102)
    - Plans - Correspondence, 1983, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 103)
    - Preface - Wass, 1984, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 104)
    - Project Permissions, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 105)
    - Project Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 18, Folder 106)
    - Publications Mailed, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 107)
    - Publication Requests, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 108)
    - Table of Contents, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 109)
    - Thorne, Kip - Book Reception, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 110)
    - UK - Bernard Isaacs, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 111)
    - UK - Alan Williams, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 112)
    - United States - Karen Davis, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 113)
    - United States - Robert L. Kane, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 114)
  - Programs, 4
    - A Study of the Feasibility of Establishing a College of the Health Sciences at the Claremont Colleges, 1972 Dec. (Box 19, Folder 115)
    - Are Older Workers "Good Buys"? - A Case Study of Days Inns of America, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 116)
    - Are Older Workers 'Good Buys'? - A Case Study of Days Inns of America - Sloan Report, 1991; 2015:FA481:001 (Item 2015:FA481:001)
    - Ageworks - A Case Study of the UK - Retailer B and Q's of Older Workers (Box 19, Folder 117)
    - Ageworks - A Case Study of the UK Retailer B and Q's Use of Older Workers - Report MB, 1991; 2015:FA481:002 (Item 2015:FA481:002)
    - Board Dinner - Christmas Remarks, 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 118)
    - Boston University - Modular Medical Integrated Curriculum, 1981 Feb., Sept. 29 (Box 19, Folder 119)
    - Boston University - Modular Medical Integrated Curriculum, 1981 Sept. 29; 2015:FA481:003 (Item 2015:FA481:003)
    - Brian Biles Press Release, 1994 Nov. 18 (Box 19, Folder 120)
    - Bridge Employment and Job Stopping in the 1980's, 1990-1991 (Box 20, Folder 121)
    - Bridge Employment and Job Stopping in the 1980's, 1990-1991; 2015:FA481:004 (Item 2015:FA481:004)
    - Carnegie Corporation - Conference on the Growing Crisis in Medical Services and Medical Education, 1966 Feb. 20-25 (Box 20, Folder 122)
    - Carter Center Reception - Harkness House, 1995 January 26 and November 18 (Box 20, Folder 123)
    - Carter Center Reception - Harkness House, 1995 Jan. 26; 2015:FA481:005 (Item 2015:FA481:005)
    - Center for Biomedical Education - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 124)
    - Center for Biomedical Education - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 125)
    - Columbia University - Center for Community Health Systems, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 126)
    - Columbia University - Center for Community Health Systems, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 127)
    - Columbia University - Center for Community Health Systems, 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 128)
    - Columbia University - Center for Community Health Systems, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 129)
    - Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Annotated Bibliography of Commission Publications - TWM - A Survey of Elderly Hispanics - Final Report, 1989 Oct. 11 (Box 21, Folder 130)
    - Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Annotated Bibliography of Commission Publications - TWM - Expanding Autonomy of the Elderly in Home Health Care Programs, 1990 March (Box 21, Folder 131)
    - Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Annotated Bibliography of Commission Publications - TWM - Improving Choices Regarding Home Care Services - Legal Impediments and Empowerments, 1990 April (Box 21, Folder 132)
    - Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Annotated Bibliography of Commission Publications - TWM - Lessons for Enhancing Consumer-Directed Approaches in Home Care, 1991 January (Box 21, Folder 133)
    - Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Annotated Bibliography of Commission Publications - TWM - Synthesis of Reports on Reforms in Long-Term Care Financing, 1988 Feb. (Box 22, Folder 134)
    - Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Staff and Commission Members - Photographs, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 135)
    - Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Staff and Commission Members - Photographs, 1989, 1991, 1996; 2015:FA481:006 (Item 2015:FA481:006)
    - Commission on the Year 2000, 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 136)
    - Commonwealth Fund, Carnegie, and AACC - Memorandum on Health Care, 1970 Feb.1 (Box 22, Folder 137)
    - Computer Based Examination (CBX Project) - Documents Vol. I, 1970-1973 (Box 22, Folder 138)
    - Computer Based Examination (CBX Project) - Documents Vol. II, 1973 Oct.-Dec. (Box 22, Folder 139)
    - Computer Based Examination (CBX Project) - Documents Vol. III, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 140)
    - Cornell University - Comprehensive Care and Teaching Program - Research Memorandums, 1955-1959 (Box 23, Folder 141)
    - Dropping Out of High School - Survey - Study Number 902066, 2993 Oct. - 1994 March (Box 23, Folder 142)
    - Effective Strategies for Helping Older Workers, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 143)
    - Einstein College of Medicine - Health Careers Program at Lincoln Hospital - Supplementary Material, 1965-1967 (Box 23, Folder 144)
    - Einstein College of Medicine - Health Careers Program at Lincoln Hospital - Supplementary Material, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - Einstein College of Medicine - Health Careers Program at Lincoln Hospital - Supplementary Material, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - Einstein College of Medicine - Health Careers Program at Lincoln Hospital - Supplementary Material, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - Einstein College of Medicine - Health Careers Program at Lincoln Hospital - Supplementary Material, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - Einstein College of Medicine - Health Careers Program at Lincoln Hospital, Vol. I, 1968 April 1 (Box 24, Folder 149)
    - Einstein College of Medicine - Health Careers Program at Lincoln Hospital, Vol.II, 1968 April 1 (Box 25, Folder 150)
    - Fellows - Harkness Program, 1969-1978 (Box 25, Folder 151)
    - Fellowships - To Graduates of the Universities of the United Kingdom - A Review, 1925-1955 (Box 25, Folder 152)
    - Health Affair Reprint - KD - Mailing, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 153)
    - Karen Davis-Margaret E. Mahoney Press Release Original, Clinton Holiday Greeting, Diplomatic, British and New Zealand Invitations, Participation and Presentation thank you letters., 1994 Sept. 13, 1996 Dec. 16, 20, 1997 Feb. 7 (Box 25, Folder 154)
    - Life Satisfaction and Older Adults, 1989-1991 (Box 25, Folder 155)
    - Life Satisfaction and Older Adults, 1989-1991; 2015:FA481:oo7 (Item 2015:FA481:007)
    - Literature Review - Working with Business to Improve Employment Opportunities for Older Americans, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - Literature Review - Working with Business to Improve Employment Opportunities for Older Americans, 1991; 2015:FA481:008 (Item 2015:FA481:008)
    - National Comparative Survey of Minority Health Care, 1995 March 20 (Box 26, Folder 157)
    - Older Workers Background Papers, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 158)
    - Permissions from Authors and Publishers - Squire, Lucy F. - Fundamentals of Roentgenology, 1962-1963 (Box 26, Folder 159)
    - Problems and Prospects of an Urban Public University - President's Biennial Report 1970-1972 - The City College of New York, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 160)
    - Retirement Preferences and Plans of Older American Workers, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 161)
    - Retirement Preferences and Plans, 1991; 2015:FA481:009 (Item 2015:FA481:009)
    - Retirement Preferences and Plans, 1991; 2015:FA481:010 (Item 2015:FA481:010)
    - Report of the Task Force on Academic Health Centers Prescription for Change, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 162)
    - Special Report - Small Group Market Reforms - A Snapshot of States' Experience, 1995 Feb. (Box 27, Folder 163)
    - Special Report - Community Rating - States Experiences, 1994 July 29 (Box 27, Folder 164)
    - Teenaged Mothers - Furstenberg, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 165)
    - Teenaged Mothers - Furstenberg Report, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 166)
    - Teenaged Mothers Seventeen Years Later, 1987-1989 (Box 27, Folder 167)
    - The Community Blood Council of Greater New York, 1964-1967 (Box 28, Folder 168)
    - The Impact of Increased Employment of Older Workers on the National Economy - Final Report - Draft, 1989 Dec. (Box 28, Folder 169)
    - The Impact of Increased Employment of Older Workers on the National Economy - Final Report - Draft, 1989 Dec. (Box 28, Folder 170)
    - The Impact of Increased Employment of Older Workers on the National Economy - Final Report - Original, 1989 Dec., 1992 June 1 (Box 28, Folder 171)
    - The Impact of Increased Employment of Older Workers on the National Economy - Final Report - Original, 1989 December, 1992 June 1; 2015:FA481:011 (Item 2015:FA481:011)
    - The Next Educational Opportunity - Career Training for Older Adults, 1992 July (Box 29, Folder 172)
    - The Sophie Davis School of Biomedical Education - The City College of New York, Vol. II, 1975-1981 (Box 29, Folder 173)
    - The Sophie Davis School of Biomedical Education - The City College of New York, Vol. III, 1975-1981 (Box 29, Folder 174)
    - University of Minnesota - Medical School, 1943 (Box 29, Folder 175)
    - Using Retirees to Fill Temporary Labor Needs - The Travelers' Experience, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 176)
    - Using Retirees to Fill Temporary Labor Needs - The Travelers' Experience, 1991; 2015:FA481:012 (Item 2015:FA481:012)
    - Why Workers Retire Early - Final Report, 1989 October (Box 29, Folder 177)
    - Why Workers Retire Early - Final Report, 1989 October; 2015:FA481:013 (Item 2015:FA481:013)
  - Publications, 5
    - The Visiting Teacher, 1921, 1926 (Box 30, Folder 178)
    - 1923 May 1 (Box 30, Folder 179)
    - Progress Report, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 180)
    - Commonwealth Fund Program for the Prevention of Delinquency - Progress Report (Box 30, Folder 181)
    - Progress Report, 1926 (Box 30, Folder 181)
    - Some Extra-Curricular Problems of the Classroom - Joint Committees on Methods of Preventing Delinquency, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 182)
    - The Role of Penalties in Criminal Law - Yale Law Journal, 1927 (Box 30, Folder 183)
    - Some Observations on the Law of Evidence - Memory - Reprint - Harvard Law Review, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 184)
    - Some Observations on the Law of Evidence - Spontaneous Exclamations - Columbia Law Review, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 185)
    - Some Extra-Curricular Problems of the Classroom, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 186)
    - Institute for Child Guidance to the Administrative Board - Report of the Board, 1928 June 30 (Box 30, Folder 187)
    - Some Observations on the Law of Evidence - The Competency of Witnesses - Reprint - Yale Law Journal, 1928 June (Box 30, Folder 188)
    - Five Years in Fargo - Child Health Demonstration Committee, 1928 May (Box 30, Folder 189)
    - Safe Drinking for Rural Schools - Rutherford County, TN. - Child Health Demonstration Committee - Reprint - The Southern Agriculturist, 1928 July 1 (Box 30, Folder 190)
    - Serving the Child in Fargo - Child Health Demonstration Committee, 1928 Nov. (Box 30, Folder 191)
    - Legal Psychological Review, 1929 January (Box 30, Folder 192)
    - Some Observations on the Law of Evidence - State of Mind in Issue - Reprint - Columbia Law Review, 1929 Feb. (Box 30, Folder 193)
    - Die Kropfbekampfung in Vorarlberg, 1929 (Box 30, Folder 194)
    - The Newsletter of the Commonwealth Fund, 1929-1934, 1936-1943, 1945-1946 (Box 30, Folder 195)
    - The Purpose and Scope of Visiting Teacher Work, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 196)
    - Facts Concerning and the Study of Civil Justice in New York - Johns Hopkins University, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 197)
    - The Institute for Child Guidance 1927-1933 (Box 31, Folder 198)
    - Report to the Legal Research Committee, 1934 May 5 (Box 31, Folder 199)
    - Medical Social Aspects in Practice - Reprint - Archives of Internal Medicine, 1934 July (Box 31, Folder 200)
    - Readers Digest - Self-Supporting College, 1938 May (Box 31, Folder 201)
    - Teachers and Behavior Problems - Digest of Children's Behavior and Teachers' Attitudes, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 202)